# Junyi Zhang

**■** junyizhang@sjtu.edu.cn ♦ Junyi42 ♦ junyi42.com

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests mainly lie in **computer vision**, **deep generative models**, and **representation learning**. I am now focusing on the **application of diffusion models**, exploring its potential for **both generation and perception scenarios**. I also have a background in action recognition, self-supervised learning, and other modalities including video, 3D, human motion, and language.

#### EDUCATION

#### SEIEE, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Major in Computer Science and Technology, GPA: 3.92 (8/108)

Shanghai, China Sept. 2020 - Present

#### Zhiyuan College, Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Major in Zhiyuan Honors Program of Engineering (Top 5%)

## **Publications**

#### Telling Left from Right: Identifying Geometry-Aware Semantic Correspondence

<u>Junyi Zhang, Charles Herrmann, Junhwa Hur, Eric Chen, Varun Jampani, Deqing Sun, Ming-Hsuan Yang.</u>
<u>Under review</u>, 2023. [Webpage] [ArXiv:2311.17034]

A Tale of Two Features: Stable Diffusion Complements DINO for Zero-Shot Semantic Correspondence Junyi Zhang, Charles Herrmann, Junhwa Hur, Luisa F. Polanía, Varun Jampani, Deqing Sun, Ming-Hsuan Yang. NeurIPS, 2023. [Webpage] [Code] [ArXiv:2305.15347]

Layout Diffusion: Improving Graphic Layout Generation by Discrete Diffusion Probabilistic Models Junyi Zhang, Jiaqi Guo, Shizhao Sun, Jian-Guang Lou, Dongmei Zhang.

ICCV, 2023. [Code] [ArXiv:2303.11589]

From Isolated Islands to Pangea: Unifying Semantic Space for Human Action Understanding

Yong-Lu Li\*, Xiaoqian Wu\*, Xinpeng Liu, Yiming Dou, Yikun Ji, <u>Junyi Zhang</u>, Yixing Li, Xudong Lu, Jingru Tan, Cewu Lu. *Under review*, 2023. [Webpage] [ArXiv:2304.00553]

#### Mining Cross-Person Cues for Body-Part Interactiveness Learning in HOI Detection

Xiaoqian Wu\*, Yong-Lu Li\*, Xinpeng Liu, Junyi Zhang, Yuzhe Wu, Cewu Lu.

ECCV, 2022. [Code] [ArXiv:2207.14192]

## EXPERIENCE

#### University of California, Merced - Vision Learning Lab

Visiting Student – Supervisor: *Prof.* Ming-Hsuan Yang

Merced, California

June 2023 - Present

• Explore and improvediffusion representations for semantic correspondence

#### Microsoft Research Asia - Data, Knowledge and Intelligence Group

Research Intern – Mentor: Dr. Shizhao Sun and Dr. Jian-Guang Lou

I 1 2022 D 2022

Beijing, China

July 2022 - Dec. 2022

• Build discrete diffusion models for layout synthesis

#### Shanghai Jiao Tong University - Machine Vision and Intelligence Group

Undergraduate Research Intern – Supervisor: *Prof.* Yong-Lu Li

Shanghai, China Oct. 2021 - Present

- Build diffusion models for interactive motion generation
- Experiment on extending multimodal action recognition to video dataset
- Experiment on incorporating human knowledge into HOI detection

# SELECTED AWARDS

SenseTime Scholarship (30 undergraduate AI researcher nationwide)	2023
Microsoft Research "Stars of Tomorrow" Certificate (Top 10% interns)	2022
Huawei Fellowship (Top 1% in honors program)	
National Scholarship (Top 0.2% nationwide, highest honor in China)	2021
Outstanding Undergraduate Scholarship, A Level, SJTU (Top 1%)	

# SKILLS

- Skills: Python (Pytorch), C/C++, html, css, Linux, LATEX, Assembly language
- Languages: English (TOEFL 105/120), Chinese (Native)

# REFERENCES

- Ming-Hsuan Yang, Professor of EECS University of California, Merced; Research Scientist, Google Research
- Deqing Sun, Research Scientist, Google Research
- Varun Jampani, Lead Researcher, Stability AI
- Jian-Guang Lou, Principal Researcher, Microsoft Research
- Shizhao Sun, Senior Researcher, Microsoft Research
- Yong-Lu Li, Assistant Professor of Computer Science Shanghai Jiao Tong University